<resources>
    <string name="app_name">interesting music</string>
    <string name="intro_topic1">Welcome , which is the starting point for beginners into the interesting and fun world of music theory. In this course, you’ll master the fundamentals of music theory and see how to analyse music from an objective standpoint which will help you listen out for things in music from the past, present and future. The introductory course is made of three core concepts which will be the backbone of the more complex concepts as you progress. The first course is Pulse and Beats which is what gives music structure. Without a pulse and beats music would lose it’s life! A pulse can be thought of as the ticking of a clock as it separates the individual ticks by one second which can be thought of as the beat. In this way a pulse keeps structure by splitting beats into equal lengths of time! If you ran faster your heart rate would increase and beat more. Since the time between beats is now shorter would you say the pulse has increased? (Yes/No) (Yes is correct answer) (If no chosen - that’s not quite right, if you think about your heart as a clock, the one second beats are now separated into half second beats meaning the pulse has increased). Pulse and beats are always there even if you cannot hear them just like your heartbeat. Your body can naturally feel a pulse when you hear music. You do this when you tap your foot to a song. Click the play button below to hear a short drum beat and try to clap or tap your foot to the pulse.</string>
    <string name="intro_topic3">Pitch is the highness or lowness of a sound. As an example a woman’s speaking tone is usually higher in pitch than a male’s speaking tone.

Individual pitches are called notes. The notes in music are named after the letters of the alphabet - A,B,C,D,E,F,G. As the alphabet goes up from A to G it increases in pitch and conversely going down decreases in pitch. However, unlike the real alphabet this musical one stops at G and repeats itself after. So the first note after G would be A and go up again until it reaches G and so on. Click below to hear all the notes starting from A.


How do we actually write pitches though? Well we use a musical staff. Notes that are higher on a staff are higher in pitch and notes that are lower are lower in pitch. Notes can be written on or between the lines. (image of notes on staff)</string>
</resources>
